<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Copyright 2016 Oliver Heimlich
Copyright 2016 Rodéric Moitié

Copying and distribution of this file, with or without modification,
are permitted in any medium without royalty provided the copyright
notice and this notice are preserved.  This file is offered as-is,
without any warranty.
-->
<component type="addon">
	<id>octave-interval</id>
	<extends>www.octave.org-octave.desktop</extends>
	<name>Interval</name>
	<summary>Real-valued interval arithmetic</summary>
	<summary xml:lang="de">Reellwertige Intervallarithmetik</summary>
	<summary xml:lang="fr">Arithmétique d'intervalles à valeurs réelles</summary>
	<description>
		<p>The interval package for real-valued interval arithmetic allows one to evaluate functions over subsets of their domain.  All results are verified, because interval computations automatically keep track of any errors.</p>
		<p>These concepts can be used to handle uncertainties, estimate arithmetic errors and produce reliable results.  Also it can be applied to computer-assisted proofs, constraint programming, and verified computing.</p>
		<p>The implementation is based on interval boundaries represented by binary64 numbers and is conforming to IEEE Std 1788-2015, IEEE standard for interval arithmetic.</p>
	</description>
	<description xml:lang="de">
		<p>Das Intervall-Paket für rellwertige Intervallarithmetik kann Funktionen über Teilmengen ihres Definitionsbereichs auszuwerten.  Alle Ergebnisse werden durch Rechnung mit Intervallschranken nachgewiesen, wobei sämtliche Fehler automatisch mitgeführt werden.</p>
		<p>Mit diesen Konzepten lassen sich ungewisse Messwerte behandeln, arithmetische Fehler abschätzen und zuverlässige Ergebnisse erzeugen.  Es kann auch für rechnergestützte Beweise, Constraintprogrammierung oder verifiziertes Rechnen angewandt werden.</p>
		<p>Die Intervallschranken werden im Zahlenformat binary64 geführt und die Umsetzung ist standardkonform zu IEEE Std 1788-2015, dem IEEE-Standard für Intervallarithmetik.</p>
	</description>
	<description xml:lang="fr">
		<p>Le paquet arithmétique d'intervalles à valeurs réelles permet d'évaluer des fonctions sur des sous-ensembles de leurs domaines.  Tous les résultats sont garantis car les calculs par intervalles permettent un suivi automatique des erreurs.</p>
		<p>Ces concepts peuvent être utilisés pour prendre en compte les incertitudes, estimer les erreurs arithmétiques, et générer des résultats fiables.  Ils peuvent également être appliqués à des preuves assistées par ordinateur, à la programmation par contraintes et à des calculs garantis.</p>
		<p>Cette implantation est basée sur des bornes d'intervalles sous forme de nombres réels 64 bits et se conforme au standard IEEE 1788-2015, standard IEEE pour l'arithmétique d'intervalles.</p>
	</description>
	<keywords>
		<keyword>interval arithmetic</keyword>
		<keyword>interval analysis</keyword>
		<keyword>interval computation</keyword>
		<keyword>parameter estimation</keyword>
		<keyword>rounding error</keyword>
		<keyword>measurement error</keyword>
		<keyword>numerical error</keyword>
		<keyword>scientific computing</keyword>
		<keyword>result verification</keyword>
		<keyword>verified result</keyword>
		<keyword>set arithmetic</keyword>
		<keyword>finite precision</keyword>
		<keyword>range</keyword>
		<keyword>interval</keyword>
		<keyword>tolerance</keyword>
		<keyword>uncertainty</keyword>
		<keyword>preimage</keyword>
		<keyword>constraint</keyword>
		<keyword>enclosure</keyword>
		<keyword>bisection</keyword>
	</keywords>
	<url type="homepage">http://octave.sourceforge.net/interval/</url>
	<url type="bugtracker">https://savannah.gnu.org/bugs/?group=octave</url>
	<metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
	<project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
	<developer_name>Octave-Forge Community</developer_name>
	<update_contact>octave-maintainers@gnu.org</update_contact>
</component>
